{
  "version": 2.0,
  "questions": [
    {
      "question": "What does Vane anemometer calculates?",
      "answers": {
        "a": "Air velocity",
        "b": "Distance",
        "c": "Acceleration",
        "d": "Momentum"
      },
      "explanations": {
        "a": "",
        "b": "",
        "c": "",
        "d": ""
      },
      "correctAnswer": "b",
      "difficulty": ""
    },
    {
      "question": "What is the range of Vane anemometer in mines?",
      "answers": {
        "a": " 01 - 05 m/sec",
        "b": "01 - 10 m/sec",
        "c": "01 - 15 m/sec",
        "d": " 01 - 20 m/sec"
      },
      "explanations": {
        "a": "",
        "b": "",
        "c": "",
        "d": ""
      },
      "correctAnswer": "c",
      "difficulty": ""
    },
    {
      "question": "The vanes are set an angle to the direction of air flow",
      "answers": {
        "a": "0.795 radian",
        "b": "0.785 radian",
        "c": "45 Degree",
        "d": "Both b and c"
      },
      "explanations": {
        "a": "",
        "b": "",
        "c": "",
        "d": ""
      },
      "correctAnswer": "b",
      "difficulty": ""
    },
    {
      "question": "Axis of Vane anemometer should be in the",
      "answers": {
        "a": "Direction parallel to the Air",
        "b": "Vertical to the direction of air",
        "c": "Inclined 30 degree",
        "d": "45 degree to the direction of air"
      },
      "explanations": {
        "a": "",
        "b": "",
        "c": "",
        "d": ""
      },
      "correctAnswer": "a",
      "difficulty": ""
    },
    {
      "question": "What does Digital Anemometer calculates ?",
      "answers": {
        "a": "Air velocity",
        "b": "Distance",
        "c": "Acceleration",
        "d": "Momentum"
      },
      "explanations": {
        "a": "",
        "b": "",
        "c": "",
        "d": ""
      },
      "correctAnswer": "a",
      "difficulty": ""
    },
    {
      "question": "Low range and high range Vane anemometer contains ____ blades",
      "answers": {
        "a": "4 & 8",
        "b": "2 & 4",
        "c": "3 & 6",
        "d": "5 & 10"
      },
      "explanations": {
        "a": "",
        "b": "",
        "c": "",
        "d": ""
      },
      "correctAnswer": "a",
      "difficulty": ""
    },
    {
      "question": "Which factor is considered to obtain correct velocity?",
      "answers": {
        "a": "Atkinson factor",
        "b": "Method factor ",
        "c": "Dust Factor",
        "d": "Friction Factor"
      },
      "explanations": {
        "a": "",
        "b": "",
        "c": "",
        "d": ""
      },
      "correctAnswer": "b",
      "difficulty": ""
    },
    {
      "question": "Method factor depends on ___________",
      "answers": {
        "a": "Size of the duct",
        "b": "Quantity of dust passing through the duct",
        "c": "Air resistance with blade of vane anemometer",
        "d": "All of these"
      },
      "explanations": {
        "a": "",
        "b": "",
        "c": "",
        "d": ""
      },
      "correctAnswer": "a",
      "difficulty": ""
    },
    {
      "question": "Approximate value of Method factor in mine is _______",
      "answers": {
        "a": "0.75",
        "b": "0.95",
        "c": "1.55",
        "d": "0.85"
      },
      "explanations": {
        "a": "",
        "b": "",
        "c": "",
        "d": ""
      },
      "correctAnswer": "d",
      "difficulty": ""
    },
    {
      "question": "What is the maximum quantity of air Vane anemometer can measure in a gallery of coal mine working under Board & Pillar method?",
      "answers": {
        "a": "216m<sup>3</sup>/sec",
        "b": "150.56 m<sup>3</sup>/sec",
        "c": "183.6 m<sup>3</sup>/sec",
        "d": "200.9 m<sup>3</sup>/sec"
      },
      "explanations": {
        "a": "",
        "b": "",
        "c": "",
        "d": ""
      },
      "correctAnswer": "c",
      "difficulty": ""
    }
  ]
}



